<documentation>
    <doc for="colorParam">
        <param name="color">Color in a <a href="https://www.questpdf.com/concepts/colors.html">valid format</a> (like <c>#FF8800</c> for orange) or from the predefined <see cref="Colors"/> set (like <c>Colors.Red.Lighten1</c>).</param>
    </doc>

    <doc for="scale.remarks">
        <remarks>
            <para>Although this adjustment modifies the space available to its inner content, some elements might use their own strategies to fill that space.</para>
            <para>For example, an Image with the <see cref="Infrastructure.ImageScaling.FitWidth" /> setting may retain its size, but its quality could vary based on the DPI setting.</para>
            <para>In contrast, text will not only appear smaller or bigger; but also a different number of words may fit each line.</para>
        </remarks>
    </doc>
    
    <doc for="scale.factorParam">
        <param name="factor">The scaling factor. Values greater than 1 enlarge the content, while values less than 1 reduce it.</param>
    </doc>

    <doc for="image.remarks">
        <remarks>
            <para>
                Please note that there is a significant difference between image resolution (number of pixels vertically and horizontally) and its physical size described in points.
                Therefore, the resolution of an image is not used for determining its physical size on the document.
            </para>

            <para>
                Multiple strategies exist for the Image element to determine its final size. 
                By default, the image fills all the available width. 
                This behavior can be customized using options within the <see cref="Fluent.ImageDescriptor">descriptor</see> class.
            </para>
            
            <para>
                Images are automatically resized and compressed based on the descriptor's setup.
                It defaults to <see cref="DocumentSettings">global document's settings</see>.
            </para>
            
            <para>Supported formats: PNG, JPEG and WEBP.</para>
        </remarks>
    </doc>

    <doc for="image.useOriginalImage">
        <summary>
            When enabled, the library does not resize the image to achieve the target DPI, nor compress it with target image quality.
        </summary>
    </doc>
    
    <doc for="image.rasterDPI">
        <summary>
            <para>Specifies the DPI (dots-per-inch) for rasterizing images.</para>
            <para>The target resolution is computed by multiplying the DPI with the physical image size on the document.</para>
            <para>Higher DPI results in superior image quality but may increase the output file size.</para>
            <para>Default DPI value is 288 DPI.</para>
        </summary>
        
        <remarks>
            If the image has lower resolution that the one calculated from the DPI setting, it will NOT be rescaled.
        </remarks>
        
        <example>
            Consider an image of dimensions 3x4 inches. Using a DPI value of 300, the final resolution translates to 900x1200 pixels.
        </example>
    </doc>

    <doc for="image.compressionQuality">
        <summary>
            <para>Controls the balance between encoding quality and file size.</para>
            <para>Opaque images are JPEG-encoded based on this setting, while images with an alpha channel default to PNG format, disregarding this option.</para>
            <para>Default is set to "high quality".</para>
        </summary>
    </doc>

    <doc for="image.descriptor">
        <returns>Descriptor allowing adjustments to image attributes, such as scaling behavior, compression quality, and target DPI.</returns>
    </doc>

    <doc for="contentDirection.ltr.remarks">
        <remarks>
            <para>This writing system is used by most of modern languages.</para>
            
            <para>
                The content direction affects various layout structures. In LTR mode, items are typically aligned to the left.
                This mode also influences the direction of items in certain layouts. For instance, in a row element with LTR mode,
                the first item is positioned on the left, while the last item is on the right.
            </para>
        </remarks>
    </doc>

    <doc for="contentDirection.rtl.remarks">
        <remarks>
            <para>This writing system is used by languages such as Hebrew, Arabic, and Persian.</para>
            
            <para>
                The content direction affects various layout structures. In RTL mode, items are typically aligned to the right.
                This mode also influences the direction of items in certain layouts. For instance, in a row element with RTL mode,
                the first item is positioned on the right, while the last item is on the left.
            </para>
        </remarks>
    </doc>
</documentation>